researchers have attempted to solve the
issue of the disembodied brains grown in
jars having circulation by growing them
inside the skulls of M this is manmade
Horrors Beyond Comprehension for those
of you who are new here this is a human
brain organoid those are its little eyes
it's pretty cute we can grow human
brains using stem cells and Petri dishes
however they tend to suffer from hypoxia
after a period of about 5 months at the
center because they're not circulated
they don't have vascularization this is
a problem while they are able to grow
the immature complex structures of a
human brain similar to that in early
fetal development and they have the
brain waves of a premature baby that
would be delta waves which is more
similar to deep sleep we just aren't
able to keep them alive long enough to
continue their development scientists
have been trying to find ways to
vascularize it one of which is
implanting it into the brain of a mouse
by doing this we're able to watch the
development of the brain waves
indefinitely within the mouse you can
read the paper apparently they didn't
have any significantly different
Behavior than other amuno compromised
mice who did not have the brain implant
but it does leave us with a very good
insight into how far we can take the
human brain organoids and how complex
they can get some really cool
applications of this kind of research
could be testing things like anticho and
anti-depressants
on your own little mini brain and see
how it reacts we can also watch drugs
impact the developing brain so we know
what we can expect when it comes to
pregnant women taking medication but
what do you think of the ethics of these
kind of experiments